[ 1950s music ]
[ man ] During the spookiest time of the year ,
there are a few guidelines
all ghosts and goblins should follow .
Always stay on sidewalks .
Never go to a stranger 's house ,
and never go out alone .
[ scary sounds ]
[ tires screech ]
- [ rock music playing ] - [ women laughing ]
[ Emma ] This was a great idea , honey , really .
It 's just magical .
It makes me wish every night was Halloween .
[ Henry ] I 'm sorry , Em .
- Wait , wait . Not yet . - [ deep breathing ]
[ Emma ] What ?
[ Henry ] You 're supposed to keep it lit .
Why ?
I don 't know , ancient tradition ?
Henry , it 's Halloween , not Hanukkah .
- Baby , I 'm lit and you 're lit . - But honey - -
[ Emma ] But our little friend here , his night 's over .
[ gasping sound ]
[ Henry ] You know , you should be more careful .
There are rules . You might upset someone .
[ Emma ] Oh , please . Who ?
[ heavy breathing continues ]
What ?
Inside . Upstairs .
Let 's take all this crap down . It looks like a crime scene .
- I 'll do it in the morning . - No , you won 't .
You 're gonna sleep until noon
and then play video games until four .
And besides , my mom is coming in the morning ,
and she 'll have an aneurysm if she sees this place .
Really ?
I 'll do it .
Go inside , put on the tape .
- [ both chuckle ] - [ deep breathing ]
I hate Halloween .
[ gasps ]
- [ car horn honks ] - [ rock music plays ]
[ man ] What took you guys so long ?
Happy Halloween .
[ screams ]
[ woman moans on TV ]
Yeah ! Oh , baby !
- [ screaming ] - [ slashing sound ]
[ groaning sound ]
Emma ?
[ gasps ]
[ screams ]
[ noisemaker and drum sounds ]
[ woman ] Werewolves , zombies and demons of every variety ,
they 've all descended on the normally sleepy town
of Warren Valley , Ohio ,
where the holiday and all of its strange traditions
are taken very seriously .
It 's only 8 : 00 and the streets are already packed
with costumed visitors ,
some to show off , others to blend in ,
but all to celebrate the magical night of Halloween ,
the one night a year when we can pretend to be
the scariest thing we can think of .
[ baby cries ]
[ woman 1 ] I am not wearing this .
It 's too small .
- My tits keep popping out . - [ woman 2 ] That 's the idea .
[ girl 1 ] I don 't know why we drove here
when there are good guys in the city .
[ girl 2 ] Fresh meat .
[ girl 3 ] It 's what we do every Halloween , Laurie .
[ Laurie ] What happened to trick-or-treating ?
[ girl 3 ] Puberty .
[ woman 4 ] Last year we were in Tampa .
[ woman 3 ] And went as sexy nurses .
[ woman 2 ] No , Janet , Tampa was two years ago .
I remember because you puked doing a guy in his pickup .
[ Janet ] I ate some bad Mexican , and it was a Jeep .
[ woman 2 ] Last year was San Diego .
We dressed as sailors and ended up with sailors .
[ Janet ] Yeah , and Maria 's sailor was a girl .
[ Maria ] So what ? She had a nice ass .
It all tastes the same to me anyway .
Ladies , there are children out here .
[ women laugh ]
[ woman 2 ] Okay , all of you come out on the count of three .
One , two , three .
[ chuckles ]
Nice .
- Laurie , come on out . - No .
- Open up . - No .
Open the door , or we 'll huff and we 'll puff ...
Come on , seriously , open up .
Fine , just don 't laugh , okay ?
Danielle , I look like I 'm five .
- Shut up , you look great . - [ both chuckle ]
It 's tradition .
Great . What does tradition say we do now ?
We meet our dates .
Two thirty-three , 30-D .
I mean , $ 234.33 .
Thanks .
You know , this might sound kind of forward , but ,
well , we 're just in town for a party tonight ,
and I was wondering what time you get off work .
Oh . Uh ...
In about 20 minutes , actually .
Yeah ? You know where Sheep 's Meadow is ?
Sure , yeah , of course .
All right . So why don 't you meet me there in 45 ?
Uh , okay , I guess .
Don 't forget your costume .
That can 't be good for your diabetes , Charlie .
Uh ...
Don 't waste a good lie on this .
It 's just candy .
Guess it 's a good thing I got more .
Why don 't you sit down , stay for a minute ?
Oh , I can 't . I have - -
Sit down , Charlie .
Your problem is simple .
You always wait for them to come to you .
If you just tried a little harder ,
you wouldn 't be a virgin at 22 .
What ? Excuse me ?
It 's practically stapled to your forehead .
Oh !
Laurie , please , do not listen to them .
Okay , the key thing is to just be yourself .
Being myself hasn 't gotten me very far .
Maybe I 'm too old-fashioned ,
but I 've always wanted my first time to be - -
- No , please , don 't say it . - Special .
Honey , listen , we 've all been there ,
but you can 't hesitate .
Watch .
That 's some big equipment you 've got there .
- Thank you . - I 'm Maria . This is Janet .
- And we have a small problem . - Really ?
We 've got this great party to go to ...
But we don 't have any dates .
Here . Help yourself .
It 's for the pumpkin , not you .
Promise .
All of mine were dull .
Ahh . Smashing jack-o ' - lanterns ?
Stealing candy ?
It 's okay .
Believe it or not , I was just like you when I was a kid .
Till my dad set me straight , that is .
See , my dad taught me tonight
is about respecting the dead ,
because this is the one night that the dead ,
and all sorts of other things , roam free ...
[ groans ]
... and pay us a visit .
Sorry .
All these traditions ,
jack-o ' - lanterns ,
putting on costumes , handing out treats ,
they were started to protect us , but nowadays ...
no one really cares .
Yeah .
[ coughing and stomach rumbling ]
I didn 't do such a good job , did I ?
What do you think ?
Hey .
You okay ?
You need a root beer ?
Oh , wait .
That 's right . There 's another tradition .
A very important one .
Always check your candy .
Hey .
Trick or ...
[ groaning ]
[ groans ]
[ knocking ]
[ children ] Trick or treat !
- We know you 're in there ! - We can see you !
[ ringing doorbell ]
- Hello ! - [ man ] Just a minute !
[ heavy thud ]
- [ all scream ] - Wait . No !
No . Shh ! Shh !
Great costume , Mr. Wilkins .
Oh . Uh ...
Uh ...
Oh , right , candy .
Thanks .
Principal Wilkins , do you think we might be able
to have your jack-o ' - lantern , please ?
You 're not gonna smash it , are you ?
No , it 's a scavenger hunt
for UNICEF .
Anything for a good cause .
Happy Halloween .
Yeah . Happy Halloween .
Didn 't you get one ?
[ cat snarling ]
- [ pop music playing ] - We 're going with that .
Are you sure about this ?
There 's gotta be one or two extra guys there .
- I could help you . - Go . I 'll meet you there .
Call me if you get into trouble .
You 're turning into Mom .
- Ouch . - [ van engine starts ]
- Just remember to be yourself . - But play hard to get .
Bye , Danielle !
[ humming ]
Hmmm .
Happy Halloween .
- [ groans ] - [ boy ] Daddy !
I 'm back from trick-or-treating !
[ whispering ] Billy . Shh .
- Please , be quiet . - [ shouts ] Why ?
Because you 'll bother the neighbors .
Now go watch Charlie Brown
and I 'll be in in a minute .
- Charlie Brown 's an asshole ! - Billy Wilkins ! Language .
[ groans ]
[ dog growls ]
[ barking ]
Shh , shh ! Uh ...
Wait , hold on .
[ hard thud ]
Come on . There you ...
[ snap ]
[ dog continues growling ]
- [ dog whimpers ] - Ah ?
Mmm , yeah .
Here you go . Go get it !
Shit .
[ door opens ]
[ man ] Spite !
[ gasps ]
Spite !
Get your ass in here .
Are you finished crapping or what ?
[ child screams ]
Who the hell is that ?
[ thud ]
I got an NRA membership in my pocket !
And a shotgun over the fireplace !
- So , get out of here before - - - It 's me , Mr. Kreeg .
Steven , Steven Wilkins .
What in God 's name are you doing down there , Wilkins ?
Hiding bodies ?
- [ chuckles ] - [ child screams ]
What did you say ?
- [ muffled scream ] - Nothing .
It 's ... The septic tank is acting up .
Is that what that smell is ?
I 'm afraid so .
- [ Mr. Kreeg ] Then fix it ! - [ child moans ]
It stinks like a dead whore out here .
- I 'm ... - [ thud ]
... trying .
[ thud ]
[ Mr. Kreeg ] Keep your kid out of my yard !
Goddamn freak .
Happy Halloween .
[ Mr. Kreeg ] Screw you !
[ door slams ]
- [ child grunts ] - [ gasps ]
[ Billy ] Daddy !
I wanna carve the jack-o ' - lantern now ,
but I need your help with the eyes .
In a minute , Billy .
And can I go to the parade with you later ?
No , Daddy has a date .
Oh !
But we haven 't done anything fun together .
How about if we make some caramel apples ,
- just like Grandpa used to ? - [ bone cracking ]
How about that ?
When ?
After we carve the jack-o ' - lantern ,
but you have to be quiet .
Okay .
[ child moans ]
But don 't forget to help me with the eyes !
" Daddy , I wanna carve a pumpkin . "
" Daddy , I wanna go to the parade . "
" Daddy , I wish Mommy was still alive . "
- [ pounding ] - [ muffled ] Wilkins , over here !
[ Mr. Kreeg continues shouting ]
Help me !
Screw you .
- Billy ! - [ talking on TV ]
I gotcha .
So , can we carve it now ?
[ screaming on TV ]
Yeah .
Let 's go downstairs .
Let 's carve a scary face this time .
A scary face it is .
[ whispering ] Wrap it around .
But don 't forget to help me with the eyes .
[ doorbell rings ]
- [ pop music playing ] - Trick or treat !
[ screams and laughs ]
Aren 't you guys adorable ?
Thanks , Mrs. Henderson .
That 's a great costume .
I know .
Isn 't it just " purr-fect " ?
You want a drink or something ? It 'll be our little secret .
Sure .
No , thanks .
- But , um ... - All right , fine .
I 'll see what I got for you .
Actually , Mrs. Henderson , we were sort of wondering if ...
- ... if you might ... - Holy shit .
... have a jack-o ' - lantern
we could borrow .
Here you go .
Now , be safe .
And watch out for monsters .
I don 't even know what that was .
Coach Taylor was in a hot-dog costume butt-fucking a pig .
- I think . And then - - - Chip . Let 's just not .
- Trick or treat . - What 'd you find ?
That 's it ?
Some asshole went down the street smashing all of them .
- [ groans ] - But we have three .
Isn 't this enough ?
Almost .
Macy , why didn 't we just start here ?
I didn 't know she 'd do this .
[ door opens ]
This is weird .
Is that Rhonda the retard ?
She 's not a retard , she 's an idiot savant .
Here she comes .
You 're on , Schrader .
Did you carve all these yourself ?
Yeah . Made my costume too .
Like it ?
I do .
I 'm Schrader .
Rhonda .
[ drums and noisemaker sounds ]
[ woman ] Let 's get another drink .
- [ kissing ] - [ moaning ]
[ screams ]
Henry .
I need help .
She 's just drunk , baby . Come on .
[ woman screams ]
You must really like Halloween .
You mean Samhain ?
What ?
Samhain , also known as All Hallows ' Eve ,
also known as Halloween .
Pre-dating Christianity , the Celtic holiday
was celebrated on the one night between autumn and winter
when the barrier between the living and dead was thinnest
and often involved rituals that included human sacrifice .
I like your eye patch .
Oh .
Great , a rock quarry .
Nice way to celebrate Halloween , Macy .
[ Sara ] Why are we here ?
To pay our respects to the dead .
What happened ? Did somebody die here ?
Wait .
Is this where ... ?
It is , isn 't it ? This is where that school - -
Shut up , Sara .
The Halloween School Bus Massacre .
Just don 't call it that .
- What 's she talking about ? - It 's this awesome town legend .
There was this bus full - -
Jesus , will you shut up and let me tell the damn story ?
You said a bad word .
[ sighs ]
It happened 30 years ago ...
on a late Halloween afternoon .
A school bus was on its usual route .
But this wasn 't your typical school bus ...
and they weren 't your typical kids .
There were eight of them ...
and they were different .
Troubled .
Disturbed .
Every day , parents put their dirty secrets on this bus
to be driven to a school miles outside of town .
[ child in Dracula costume ] 3260 .
3264 .
3266 .
[ Macy ] But that day ...
the driver took a different route .
Wrong way .
[ Macy ] And instead of taking the students home ...
he drove the bus to an abandoned rock quarry .
This rock quarry .
What the kids didn 't know was that over the years ,
their parents had become exhausted ,
embarrassed .
And they were willing to do anything to ease their burden .
So , one day ,
the parents approached the bus driver and made him an offer .
Shh .
[ Macy ] With the money they collected together ,
they asked him to do the unthinkable .
It almost worked perfectly .
Wrong way .
Home . Home .
I wanna go home .
Home .
[ bus engine revs ]
Home . Home .
Home ! Go home !
Home .
[ Macy ] The driver was never heard from again .
[ wheezing ]
[ Macy ] As for the bus ,
some say it sank so deep
that it couldn 't be found .
Others say the town just didn 't want it to be found .
For all we know , it 's still down there ...
and so are those kids .
You are so full of shit .
Really ?
Then I guess you won 't mind being first .
First what ?
Eight victims ,
eight jack-o ' - lanterns ...
each one representing a lost soul .
So , we 're going to leave them by the side of the lake
as an offering to those who died .
Oh .
[ electrical zapping ]
Is that one of yours ?
Yes .
It 's very pretty .
Thank you .
It can only hold three ... safely .
I 'll send the keys back up .
You guys bring the rest .
Uh ... Okay .
[ cell phone rings ]
- Hello ? - Who 's your favorite big sister ?
You there ?
Yeah . Hi .
So , there 's a guy here who really wants to meet you .
Is he young ?
Cute ?
Uh ... Yeah .
Yeah , no , you could say that .
He 's , uh , he 's really , really nice .
So , he 's hideous .
Just get your ass over here . Beggars can 't be choosers .
Nice .
Great .
Not now , Andrew .
- Josh . - Whatever .
[ howling sound ]
Werewolves .
Very funny .
[ loud metallic click ]
[ Sara ] That bus is around here somewhere .
I think it 's over here .
[ Schrader ] Over where ? I can 't see shit in this fog .
Think I found a dead retard .
- [ Sara ] That 's me , asshole . - [ Schrader ] Like I said .
[ Sara ] Both of you shut up and keep looking .
[ Schrader ] There 's something moving by that rock .
- [ Macy ] I can 't see . - [ Sara ] Jesus , what is that ?
[ Sara screams ] Help me !
[ Macy ] Sara ! Where 's Sara ?
[ Sara ] Run !
- [ Schrader ] Nowhere to go ! - I wanna go back up !
[ girl screams ]
[ whimpers ]
Macy ?
Schrader ? Sara ?
Aren 't you coming ?
Okay , stay here .
Don 't let the candles go out and they 'll protect you , okay ?
[ whimpering ]
[ screams ]
[ munching ]
[ Schrader ] Oh , shit .
[ Sara ] Is she dead ?
Hey .
- [ screams ] - [ groans ]
[ gasping ]
[ Schrader ] Rhonda ?
Rhonda ?
[ Rhonda sobs ]
And it was all going so well .
- You 're all dead ! - Rhonda , calm down .
It was all just a trick .
Look , none of this is real .
It was just a trick .
A bad joke .
I 'd say it was a pretty good one .
Shut up .
Here , let me see .
Does it hurt ?
[ sobbing ]
Go pack everything up . We 're leaving .
Says who ?
Macy , she 's scared out of her mind .
What else do you want ?
Let 's go .
This one 's still lit .
If this was all a trick , then how did the school bus get here ?
That part 's true .
What happened to the bus driver ?
I don 't know , Chip .
- [ distant spooky sounds ] - What ?
I didn 't say anything .
I 'm not in the mood .
It wasn 't me .
[ spooky echoing sounds ]
What is that ?
[ ghostly voices ]
[ screaming ]
Not again .
- [ Macy ] Over here ! - Wait here .
[ Sara ] Help us !
[ Macy ] Schrader !
[ screaming ]
[ screams ]
- Schrader ! - What the hell ?
We have to go . We have to get out of here .
- Calm down . - We have to go !
- Look , Macy - - - Listen to me !
We heard voices . There are other people here .
[ ghostly sounds ]
What is that ?
[ sobbing ]
[ screaming ]
No ! Run !
Rhonda , open the gate !
- Let us in , please ! - Open the gate !
Open the gate , please .
Come on .
Open the gate !
- No ! Rhonda , look at me . - What are you doing ?
It 's not a trick , it 's real .
Come back !
Where is she going ?
[ Schrader ] Rhonda !
- [ screaming ] - [ slashing sounds ]
[ screaming stops ]
[ rustling sound ]
[ footsteps ]
I 'm not in the mood , so just come on out !
[ screams ]
[ pop music playing ]
[ woman ] Oh , my God . She 's so funny .
No , thanks .
She 's a big girl . She can take care of herself .
I wish that were true .
Mom always said she was the runt of the litter .
[ gasps ]
[ low growl ]
My , my ,
what big eyes you have .
[ screams ]
So , where 's this guy you 're setting her up with ,
the nice one ?
[ screams ]
Laurie .
Oh , my God .
[ indistinct whispering ]
Please , help me .
There she is .
Laurie , what 's going on ?
You 're late .
Sorry . It took longer than I thought .
What did he do to you ?
I listened to their advice and played hard to get .
He bit me .
Well , at least you made it . Drink ?
Sure .
[ indistinct chatter ]
Come here .
Please .
Say " ah . "
[ moans ]
Huh . Not bad .
[ groans ]
What 's your name , honey ?
Steven .
- Steven ? - Steven Wilkins .
I 'm glad you 're her first , I really am .
I like you .
Who are you people ?
[ chuckles ]
[ screams ]
[ groans ]
I 'm nervous .
Hey .
You 're gonna be fine .
Just be yourself .
[ rock music playing ]
It 's my first time , so ...
just bear with me .
What are you doing ?
[ Steven screams ]
My , my ,
what big eyes you have .
[ howling ]
[ chomping ]
[ wheezing ]
[ locks clicking ]
Trick or ... treat .
[ low growl ]
[ all scream ]
[ growling ]
[ wheezing ]
[ man ] You push it in , you slide the food in .
It pops right out , okay ?
I 'm gonna take this device .
I 've done it a few times already .
Inside here ...
I 'm gonna show the folks how to put it on the spit rod .
It 's so darn easy .
I take the meat , and all I 'm gonna do
is just center it like this .
It goes down .
I 'll put the wheel on . It 's as simple as this .
This is about a seven-pound pork loin roast .
I 'll put it in the machine ,
I 'll slide it back , put up the window .
- You set it , and ... ? - [ TV audience ] Forget it !
Right . I 'm gonna go over to the pork loin roast over here now ...
and I 'm gonna take this one out .
This has been done - -
[ woman ] It 's only eight o 'clock
and the streets are already packed with costumed visitors ,
some to show off , others to blend in ,
but all to celebrate the magical night of Halloween .
[ woman screams on TV ]
[ man ] Baked goods and crops were left out
as offerings for the dead ,
a custom now known as trick-or-treating .
Christ .
[ man ] ... revolutionary . Now look .
Let me just start cutting this over here so that folks can see .
[ whimpers ]
Isn 't this beautiful ? Look at this over here , folks , huh ?
[ dog barks ]
[ dog growls ]
[ object creaking ]
- [ gasping ] - [ child giggling ]
[ rapid footsteps ]
[ giggling ]
[ dog barks ]
Happy Halloween .
Spite ?
[ Spite chomps and growls ]
Spite .
Get your ass in here .
Are you finished crapping or what ?
- [ child screams ] - [ man gasps ]
- Who the hell is that ? - [ man groans ]
I 've got an NRA membership in my pocket ...
and a shotgun over the fireplace ,
so get out of here before I - -
[ Steven ] It 's me , Mr. Kreeg .
Steven . Steven Wilkins .
What ... ? What in God 's name are you doing down there , Wilkins ?
- Hiding bodies ? - [ chuckles ]
[ heavy breathing ]
- [ Mr. Kreeg ] What did you say ? - [ Steven ] Nothing .
The septic tank is acting up .
Well , fix it !
It stinks like a dead whore out here .
- [ Steven ] I 'm ... trying . - [ body thuds ]
Keep your kid out of my yard !
Goddamn freak .
[ Steven ] Happy Halloween .
Screw you !
[ Spite barks ]
Get the hell off my ... !
- [ growls ] - [ Spite barks ]
[ pattering feet ]
- [ Spite barks ] - [ child giggles ]
Well , zip-a-dee-doo-dah .
Spite ?
[ door creaks ]
[ whistling ]
[ gasps ]
[ Spite barks and yelps ]
[ cocks gun ]
[ wheezing ]
Spite ?
[ feet pattering ]
[ gasps ]
Who the hell are you ?
[ screams ]
- [ glass cracking ] - [ screams ]
[ gasps ]
[ child giggling ]
[ screams ]
Wilkins ! Wilkins !
Over here ! Wilkins !
Wilkins , help me , goddamn it !
Help me ! Wilkins !
Help me !
[ Mr. Kreeg screams ]
- [ feet pattering ] - [ chomping ]
[ groans ]
- [ operator ] 911 , please hold . - Hello ? Hello ?
[ hold music playing ]
911 , what is your emergency ?
Yeah , I - - I 'd - - I 'd like to report ...
Hello ?
Hello ? Hello ?
[ feet pattering ]
[ screams ]
You gotta be fucking kidding me .
[ pattering ]
Oh , no .
[ gasping ]
[ crunching ]
- [ bones snap ] - [ screams ]
[ knocking ]
[ lock clicks ]
[ all ] Trick or treat .
Thank you .
Thanks , Mr. Kreeg .
Great mummy costume .
Thank you .
[ tires screech ]
[ all laughing ]
[ kids giggle ]
[ woman ] This was a great idea , honey .
It 's just magical .
It makes me wish every night was Halloween .
I 'm sorry , Em .
Wait , wait . Not yet .
What ?
You 're supposed to keep it lit .
Why ?
I don 't know , ancient tradition ?
Henry , it 's Halloween , not Hanukkah .
Baby , I 'm lit , and you 're lit .
But your little friend here ? His night 's over .
[ Henry ] You know , you should be more careful . There are rules .
You might upset someone .
[ Emma ] Oh , please . Who ?
[ knocking ]
[ ghostly murmurings ]
Trick or treat .
[ screaming ]